about

What started as an interest for Visual Design during the years I studied Industrial and Product Design at the Ion Mincu University of Architecture, turned into a UI/UX career. My degree in Product Design helped me through the years in understanding what users need, what their goals are when using a (digital) product and how the most simple UX solution could make their life or work better.

And even though I currently work as a UI/UX Designer, Graphic Design and Visual Art remain the things closest to my heart, as being the ones that brought me to this field. On the other hand, UI/UX design allowed me to combine both the visuals with the technical and more analytical part of creating a product (I started doing web design right after graduating university, making portfolio websites and landing pages).

Product design isn't just buzz words, it'l all about making great products with the magic tool of good design.

Proven experience in

- Designing interfaces for both mobile and web applications
- Solving problems for complex products that ease and anticipate the user's interaction
- Creating design systems and visual guidelines
- Wireframing and prototyping
- Collaborating with cross-functional engineering teams
- Branding and concept development
- Visual design

My technical strengths include tools like: Sketch, Invision, Balsamiq, Adobe XD, Marvel, Figma, Axure, Photoshop, Illustrator, Jira, Confluence

OS: MacOS (prefered), Windows

monica ionescu

ui | ux designer

Email: monisse.designs@gmail.com Behance Portfolio: https://www.behance.net/monicaio





experience

UI | UX Designer | Bitdefender

Jul 2019 - Present (Remote)

Bitdefender is a global cybersecurity and antivirus software company that develops and sells security products and services. As a UX and UI Designer my works consists of:

- Work on new and existing core products and features, while finding the best design solutions to UX problems
- Enhance user's interaction with business products while conducting all stages of the design process
- Research, design wireframes and iterate ideas based on functionality and client's feedback
- Turn the low-fidelity wireframess into clean and user friendly final products
- Create design systems, visual guidelines and UI components
- Work closely with the development team to ensure a successful implementation of the provided design
- Software tools used: Sketch, Invision,
 Adobe XD, Axure, Figma, Balsamiq,
 Photoshop, Illustrator, Jira, Confluence

UI | UX Designer | Groupe Renault

Mar 2019 - Jul 2019

Worked as a UX & UI Designer for Renault Digital Finance Hub, an Agile start-up subsidiary of the Renault Groupe, aiming to digitalize the core business for its employees, partners and clients. The products I worked at were mostly financial digital products. My responsibilities:

- Collaborated with multidisciplinary teams
 (business and engineering) in an
 Agile/Scrum way of working environment
- Conducted user interviews, research and sketched ideas based on functionality in order to identify the best possible solution that brings value to the product
- Created personas, user journey maps and user flows
- Iterated and designed low and hi-fidelity prototypes according to business requirements and client's feedback
- Designed and delivered crisp and beautiful
 UI that also embraces the brand alignment
- Helped the engineering team to understand the specs of the final design and handled a clear and easy hand-off process
- Software tools used: Sketch, Invision,
 Balsamiq, Marvel, Photoshop, Illustrator, Jira,
 Confluence

UI | UX Designer | Tremend Software Consulting

CAN THE PROPERTY OF THE PERSON WAS ASSESSED.

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

Tremend Software Consulting is a software engineering company with over 12 years of experience in developing highly complex solutions for companies around the world, specialized in delivering enterprise platforms, IoT and business solutions for leading companies in banking, telecom, automotive, commerce, retail and professional services. Some of my professional accomplishments that reflect my qualifications during the time I spent working at Tremend are:

- Solved user experience challenges, while adhering to style standards on fonts, colors and images.
- Designed user interfaces, like websites and mobile apps, while conducting layout adjustments based on client feedback.
- Developed UI mockups and prototypes that clearly illustrate how sites function and look like
- Software tools used: Sketch, Invision, Balsamiq, Photoshop, Illustrator, Jira, Confluence

Freelance UI | UX | Visual Designer

Jan 2012 - Mar 2019 (Remote)

I have been working as a designer on 99designs for a few years, being very keen on the competitive nature of the platform. I had the pleasure of working with a lot of clients from different places around the world, including USA, Denmark, Germany, Australia etc. During this time, I outgrew myself and learnt how important are communication skills when dealing with clients, respecting deadlines and coming up with great designs, adapted for their business needs. My projects included: UI for mobile apps and websites, social media campaigns and banners, brochures, posters, branding and logos.

Tools and technologies: Sketch, Figma, Adobe XD, Photoshop CC, Illustrator CC, Balsamiq, Invision, Marvel

Visual Designer | B&B collection

Jan 2014 - Aug 2018

B&B collection is the leading importer, retailer and distributor of brand watches and jewellery in Romania, as well as representing franchises for Chopard, Swarovski and Fossil. Some of my professional accomplishments while working for B&B collection are the following:

- · Created visual concepts for marketing campaigns, online and instore.
- Developed web design graphics for company's websites and social media networks.
- Conducted research, gathered assets, chose fonts, color palettes and created layouts for company's consumer brochures and other print media.
- Designed logos, brand promotional materials and marketing collaterals.
- Software tools used: Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign

education

Bachelor's Degree and Master's Degree in Product Design 2006 - 2011 | Ion Mincu University of Architecture and Planning, Product Design section

courses & certificates

- Axure RP for UX Design | Lynda.com | Jul 2019
- User Experience (UX) The Ultimate Guide to Usability and UX | Udemy | Oct 2018
- Mastering Mobile App Design With Sketch 3 | Devslopes.com | Sep 2018
- Master Android App Design with Material Design | Udemy.com | Aug 2018
- Wireframing with Balsamiq Mockups | Udemy | Jul 2018
- Workflow of Responsive Web Design from Wireframes to Style Guides | Udemy.com | Jun 2018
- UI Design with Photoshop | Udemy | Mar 2018

awards & achievements

As a versatile designer, I have always tried to expand my knowledge by constantly learning and participating to international contests. The most significant achievements that I received are:

- Winner of the global design contest from HUGO Fragrances, HUGO Create BerlinStencil Art | Jun 2011
- Semifinalist in the Adobe Design Achievement Awards Photocollage category | Aug 2010